Guide to the Yehuda Amichai Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Material, 1987-1998; Series VII; 1.88; (5 boxes)
  - Sound Recordings
    - Audiocassettes
      - "Fall Poetry Series, 1986, Yehuda Amichai, Chana Bloch", 1; 01:08:39 (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369721)
      - "Gam ha-egrof hu kaf petuhah", 1996 January 3; 1; 00:04:25 (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369739)
      - "Jerusalem Live at the Dela Courte Theatre, Central Park, NY, 1992 September; 1; 01:01:45; High frequency background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369747)
      - "Jerusalem: Original Demo", undated; 1; 01:18:51; The program sounds distorted at times. (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369754)
      - "Poems to a Listener: Series 7, Yehuda Amichai", 1992 Summer-1993 Fall; 1; 00:29:56 (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369762)
      - "Shaat ha-hesed: Shirim II, VII, I, IV", undated; 1; 00:08:35 (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369770)
      - "Ve-shuv kemo tamid be-Erets Yisrael", undated; 1; 00:38:30; Static on the tape can be heard. (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369788)
      - "Yael Gorman", undated; 1; 00:20:34 (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369796)
      - "Yehuda Amichai's Poetry in Many Languages", undated; 1; 00:22:11; Background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369804)
    - Other Recordings
      - "The Cameran Singers Choral Music from Israel", [1992?] (Box 74, Folder 1977)
      - "Erev shire meshorerim", 1994 (Box 74, Folder 1978)
      - "Rotsim lishon; rotsim le-hishtagea", 1994 (Box 74, Folder 1979)
      - "Tosefet la-hazon ha-shalom", n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1980)
      - "Zikhru ve-hizkiru", n.d. (Box 74, Folder 1981)
        Empty CD case
      - Untitled, undated; 1; 00:25:57 (Box 98, Item barcode 39002099369812)
        Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Moving Image Material
    - Video Recordings
      - "Where Poems Come From," produced and directed by Lewis MacAdams and John Dorr, Lannan Literary Series, 1989; GENMSS572_0001; 1; 01:01:05; PAL (Box 100, Item barcode 39002093672146)
      - "Yehuda Amichai," produced and directed by Lewis MacAdams and John Dorr, Lannan Literary Series #10 (2 copies), 1989; GENMSS572_0002; 1; 01:00:31; Only one copy was reformatted. (Box 100, Item barcode 39002093672153)
      - "Yehuda Amichai Poetry Evening, Tokyo", 1993 Feb 16; GENMSS572_0003; 1; 01:45:17; PAL (Box 100, Item barcode 39002093672161)
      - "Yehuda Amichai Poetry Evening, Tokyo", 1993 Feb 16; GENMSS572_0004; 1; 00:58:50; The tape suffers from oxide shedding toward the middle and the end. (Box 100, Item barcode 39002093672179)
      - "ha-Yom bo nolad ha-Mashiah", n.d.; GENMSS572_0005; 1; 01:00:39 (Box 100, Item barcode 39002093672187)
      - "You Me Jerusalem," directed by Micha Peled and George [Khleifi?], [1995]; GENMSS572_0006; 1; 00:55:59 (Box 100, Item barcode 39002093672195)
      - "10vor10 Sondersendung Live aus Jerusalem", 1993 Sep 7; GENMSS572_0007; 1; 00:32:50 (Box 100, Item barcode 39002093672203)
      - "Herinneringen en enn Nachtmerrie," Poetry International Rottterdam 1988, directed by Henk van Bruggen, GENMSS572_0008; 1; 00:31:57 (Box 99, Item barcode 39002093672211)
      - "Honorary Degrees Conferment Ceremony ... Tel Aviv, University", 1995; GENMSS572_0009; 1; 01:13:21; PAL (Box 99, Item barcode 39002093672229)
      - "Lashon ha-marot", 1993; GENMSS572_0010; 1; 00:38:33 (Box 99, Item barcode 39002093672237)
      - "Mishmar ha-emek", 1998 Jun 12; GENMSS572_0011; 1; 01:32:42 (Box 99, Item barcode 39002093672245)
      - "Poëzie is een daad," [with] Reza Allamehzadeh and Lies Janssen, rvu, 1996; GENMSS572_0012; 1; 00:44:55 (Box 99, Item barcode 39002093672252)
      - "Reayon im... 1996", GENMSS572_0013; 1; 00:33:12; A time code runs through part of the video. (Box 99, Item barcode 39002093672260)
        A 33-minute segment of an interview with Yehuda Amichai is encoded.
      - "Tekes haanakat toare kavod shel Universitat Tel-Aviv", 1995; GENMSS572_0014; 1; 01:13:54 (Box 99, Item barcode 39002093672278)
    - Motion Pictures
      - "Elem valma", n.d. (Box 76, Folder 1998-2000)
      - "Nights to Come - 57", n.d. (Box 77, Folder 2001)
- Personal Papers, 1959-1998; Series VIII; 1.26; (3 boxes)
  Series VIII, Personal Papers, is arranged alphabetically by material type.
  - Addresses and phone numbers (Box 78, Folder 2002-2003)
  - Artwork and drawings, 1989-1996, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2004)
    Includes drawing by Sarah Hartman and paintings by Zivko A. Popovski
  - Biographical material, 1995-1997, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 2005)
  - Blueprints, n.d.
  - Calendars, 1983-1989 (Box 78, Folder 2006-2011)
  - Calendars, 1989-1997 (Box 79, Folder 2012-2019)
  - Calendars, 1997-1998 (Box 79, Folder 2020)
  - Contracts, 1988-1997 (Box 80, Folder 2021)
  - Directions, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2022)
  - Empty folders and envelopes, 1997, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2023-2024)
  - Financial records, 1977-1997, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2025-2027)
  - Identity and membership cards, 1982-1997, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2028)
  - Index to unidentified work (Box 80, Folder 2029)
  - Insurance documents, 1993 (Box 80, Folder 2030)
  - Israel Defense Force documents, 1959-1992 (Box 80, Folder 2031)
  - Lists of names, 1982-1992, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2032)
  - Lists of poems, 1977, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2033)
  - Loose notes, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2034)
  - [Magnet?], n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2035)
  - Medical records, 1986 Mar 5
  - Permission Request form, 1995 Oct 3 (Box 80, Folder 2036)
  - Phone card, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2037)
  - Photocopies of original wrappers, 1995-1996, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2038-2039)
  - Photocopy of passport, 1998 Jul 8 (Box 80, Folder 2040)
  - Quill pen, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2041)
  - Schedules and itineraries, 1979-1996, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2042)
  - Souvenir (Bulgarian?), n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2043)
  - Wahlhaus family tree, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 2044)
- 2007 Addition, Series IX; 0.21; (1 box)
  Series IX, 2007 Addition, is housed in one box and consists of four DVD disks containing recordings of the keynote and other presentations from the "Poetics and Politics in Yehuda Amichai's World" conference sponsored by the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library 20-21 October, 2007.
  Box 109 (born digital): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - "Amichai Conference", 2007 (Box 109, Folder 2261-2264)
- Oversize, 1958-1999; 19.40; (14 boxes) + 9 broadside
  - Invitation for International Center for Peace in the Middle East (In Series I), 1988 (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2045)
  - Letter from Israel. Misrad ha-hinukh, ha-tarbut veha-sport (In Series I), 1993 Feb 24 (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2046)
  - Envelope from Israel. Shagrirut (China) (In Series I), 1994 Jan 18 (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2047)
  - Clipping from Israel. Shagrirut (Dominican Republic) (In Series I), 1991 Sep 8 (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2048)
  - Copy of clipping from Israel. Shagrirut (Germany: West) (In Series I), n.d. (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2049)
  - Letter from Jordan Kramer (In Series I), 1987 Jan (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2050)
  - Printed poem by Perla Schwartz (In Series I), n.d. (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2051)
  - Correspondence from Universitah ha-Ivrit bi-Yerushalayim (In Series I), 1985, n.d. (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2052)
  - Clipping from first name only correspondence (In Series I), 1995 Jun 15 (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2053)
  - Letter from unidentified (In Series I), 1995 Apr 30 (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2054)
  - Empty envelopes (In Series I), 1985-1993 (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2055)
  - Holograph draft for Sefer ha-Lailah ha-gadol (In Series II), n.d. (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2056)
  - Envelope to ha-Zanav ha-shamen shel ha-Numah (In Series II), 1987 Jul 1 (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2057)
  - "Vorwort" to unidentified text (In Series II), n.d. (Box 81 (Oversize), Folder 2058)
  - Galley proof for Lo-me akhshav, lo-mi-kan (In Series II), [1963?] (Box 82 (Oversize), Folder 2059-2060)
  - Scripts, [typescript mimeograph?], Ninah me-Ashkelon (In Series II), n.d. (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2061)
  - Printed publicity for Amen (In Series II) (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2062)
  - Holograph drafts for Gam ha-egrof hayah pa am yad petuhah ve-etsbaot (In Series II), n.d. (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2063)
  - Printed excerpts of Gam ha-egrof hayah pa am yad petuhah ve-etsbaot (In Series II), 1989 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2064)
  - Holograph drafts for Me-ahore kol zeh mistater osher gadol (In Series II), n.d. (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2064a)
  - [Early] holograph drafts for Patuah sagur patuah (In Series II), 1991-96 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2065)
  - [Later] holograph drafts for Patuah sagur patuah (In Series II), 1996 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2066)
  - Proof page to Patuah sagur patuah (In Series II), 1998 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2066a)
  - [Early] holograph draft for Shalvah gedolah (In Series II), n.d. (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2067)
  - [Later] holograph draft for Shalvah gedolah (In Series II), 1979-1980 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2068)
  - Proof of "A Bird at Dawn is Singing," corrected (In Series II), 1978 Sep 27 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2069)
  - Proof, Master, 1st pass, Time (In Series II), 1978 Sep 30 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2070)
  - Proof, Dupe, 1st past, Time (In Series II), 1978 Sep 30 (Box 83 (Oversize), Folder 2071)
  - Broadside for "ha-Kiti le-naarti" (In Series II), [1992?] (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2072)
  - Broadside for "ha-Tahanah" (In Series II) (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2073)
  - Holograph draft for "Tanakh" (In Series II) (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2074)
  - Arabic translations (In Series II), n.d. (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2075)
  - Chinese translations (In Series II), n.d. (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2076)
  - English translations (In Series II), 1978-1988, n.d. (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2077)
  - English translations (In Series II), 1986, 1988 (Box bsd, folder 2077a)
  - German translations (In Series II), n.d. (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2078)
  - Musical setting for "Aval mah asita lemaan nafshekha?" (In Series II), 1984 (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2079)
  - Printed program for "Contemporary Sounds" (In Series II), 1987 May 23 (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2080)
  - Musical setting for "Geshem ba-sadeh kerav" (In Series II), 1983 (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2081)
  - Draft for "Natati le-metargamim li-khetov" (In Series II), n.d. (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2082)
  - Galley proof to Shual ha-mahashavah by Ted Hughes (In Series III), 1996 (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2083-2084)
  - Photocopy of "Yehuda Amichai: Il dramma di Israele" by Ted Hughes (In Series III), n.d. (Box 84 (Oversize), Folder 2085)
  - Announcements for appearances by Yehuda Amichai (In Series VI), 1967-1997, n.d. (Box bsd, folder 2085a)
  - Announcements for other events (In Series VI), 1980 Sep 9 (Box 85, Folder 2086)
  - Ben-Gurion University of the Negev honorary degree (In Series VI), 1999 (Box 85, Folder 2087)
  - Israel Prize (In Series VI), 1982 (Box 85, Folder 2088)
  - Municipality of Jerusalem citation (In Series VI), 1996 Jan 17 (Box 85, Folder 2089)
  - Struga Poetry Festival award (In Series VI) (Box 85, Folder 2090)
  - Universitat Tel Aviv honorary degree (In Series VI), 1995 May 21 (Box 85, Folder 2091)
  - Printed ephemera for awards (In Series VI) (Box 85, Folder 2092)
  - Palmach statement (In Series VI), 1993 Jun 10 (Box 85, Folder 2093)
  - Brochures and promotional material (In Series VI), 1980-1984, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 2094)
  - Brochures and promotional material (In series VI) (Box bsd, folder 2094a)
  - Clippings in Arabic (In Series VI), 1990, n.d. (Box 86 (Oversize), Folder 2095)
  - Clippings in Chinese (In Series VI), 1993 (Box 86 (Oversize), Folder 2096)
  - Clippings in Croatian (In Series VI), n.d. (Box 86 (Oversize), Folder 2097)
  - Clippings in Dutch (In Series VI), 1978-1994, n.d. (Box 86 (Oversize), Folder 2098)
  - Clippings in English (In Series VI), 1967-1989 (Box 86 (Oversize), Folder 2099-2102)
  - Clippings in English (In Series VI), 1990-1999, n.d. (Box 87 (Oversize), Folder 2103-2105)
  - Clippings in French (In Series VI), 1988-1994 (Box 87 (Oversize), Folder 2106)
  - Clippings in German (In Series VI), 1969-1997, n.d. (Box 87 (Oversize), Folder 2107-2108)
  - Clippings in Hebrew (In Series VI), 1958-1982 (Box 88 (Oversize), Folder 2109-2111)
  - Clippings in Hebrew (In Series VI), 1982-1999 (Box 89 (Oversize), Folder 2112-2114)
  - Clippings in Hebrew (In Series VI), n.d. (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2115-2117)
  - Clippings in Hungarian (In Series VI), 1968 (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2118)
  - Clippings in Italian (In Series VI), 1988, 1995 (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2119)
  - Clippings in Japanese (In Series VI), 1993, n.d. (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2119a)
  - Clippings in Macedonian (In Series VI), 1994-1995 (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2120)
  - Clippings in Romanian (In Series VI), 1969 Oct 17 (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2121)
  - Clippings in Russian (In Series VI), 1993 (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2122)
  - Clippings in Spanish (In Series VI), 1970, n.d. (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2123)
  - Clippings in Swedish (In Series VI), 1988, 1991 (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2124)
  - Clippings in unidentified languages (In Series VI), n.d. (Box 90 (Oversize), Folder 2125)
  - International Writers' Conference poster (In Series VI), 1988 (Box 91 (Oversize), Folder 2125a)
  - Poetry International '67 posters (In Series VI), 1967 (Box bsd, folder 2125b)
  - Poetry International Rotterdam (In Series VI), 1974-1995 (Box bsd, folder 2125c)
  - Conference and event material (In Series VI) (Box 91 (Oversize), Folder 2126)
  - Conference and event material (In Series VI), 1971, 1981 (Box bsd, folder 2126a)
  - Mabat (In Series VI), 1988 Apr (Box 91 (Oversize), Folder 2127)
  - American Poetry Review (In Series VI), 1973-1996 (Box 91 (Oversize), Folder 2128-2130)
  - Bananas (In Series VI), 1979 (Box 91 (Oversize), Folder 2131)
  - The Cleveland Jewish News (In Series VI) (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2132)
  - Contact (In Series VI), 1991 Jul 26 (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2133)
  - Hungry Mind Review (In Series VI), 1993 (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2134)
  - The Jerusalem Post (In Series VI), 1988, 1991 (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2135)
  - The Kansas City Jewish Chronicle (In Series VI), 1981 Oct 9 (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2136)
  - The London Review of Books (In Series VI) (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2137)
  - Modern Poetry in Translation (In Series VI), 1965 (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2138)
  - The New York Times Book Review (In Series VI), 1968-1986 (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2139)
  - The New York Times Magazine (In Series VI), 1986 Jun 8 (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2140)
  - SDSU Report, 1985 (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2141)
  - T News, 1994 Jan (Box 92 (Oversize), Folder 2142)
  - The Times Literary Supplement (In Series VI), 1976-1988 (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2143)
  - Yale Weekly Bulletin & Calendar (In Serier VI), 1994 Oct (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2144)
  - Allgemeine Jüdische Wochenzeitung (In Series VI), 1980-1981 (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2145)
  - Neue Jüdische Nachrichten (In Series VI) (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2146)
  - ha-Aretz (In Series VI), 1990, 1999 (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2147)
  - Ba-mahaneh (In Series VI), 1976, n.d. (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2148)
  - Hadashot Philco (In Series VI), 1972 (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2149)
  - Hotam (In Series VI), 1972, 1988 (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2150)
  - Maariv (In Series VI), 1992 (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2151)
  - Oko: Makedonska Revija za Literatura (In Series VI), 1995 (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2152)
  - Aurora (In Series VI), 1989 (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2153)
  - El Obseravor (In Series VI), 1992 Jun 14 (Box 93 (Oversize), Folder 2154)
  - Exhibition posters (In Series VI), 1995 (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2155)
  - Exhibition poster (In Series VI), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 2155a)
  - Printed maps (In Series VI), n.d. (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2156)
  - Printed maps (In Series VI), 1997 Apr (Box bsd, folder 2156a)
  - Road Atlas of North America (In Series VI) (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2157)
  - Addresses and phone numbers (In Series VIII), [1993?] (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2158)
  - Artwork and drawings (In Series VIII) (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2159)
  - Blueprints (In Series VIII), n.d. (Box bsd, folder 2159a)
  - Empty folders and envelopes (In Series VIII), 1997, n.d. (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2160)
  - Lists of poems (In Series VIII), n.d. (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2160a)
  - Medical records (In Series VIII), 1986 Mar 5 (Box 94 (Oversize), Folder 2161)
- Restricted Papers, 1964-1993; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Restricted. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  Journals, 1964-1966, 1993.
  - Journals, 1964 (Box 95, Folder 2162-2164)
  - Journals, 1965 (Box 95, Folder 2165-2168)
  - Journals, 1965-1966 (Box 95, Folder 2169)
  - Journals, 1966 (Box 95, Folder 2170-2174)
  - Journals, 1966 (Box 96, Folder 2175-2181)
  - Journals, 1993 (Box 96, Folder 2182)
- Restricted Fragile Material, 4.42; (6 boxes) + 6 cold storage
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Correspondence (In Series I) (Box 97, Folder 2183-2190)
  - Correspondence (In Series I) (Box 97, Folder 2191-2198)
  - Correspondence (In Series I) (Box 97, Folder 2199-2206)
  - Correspondence (In Series I) (Box 97, Folder 2207-2214)
  - Correspondence (In Series I) (Box 97, Folder 2215-2216)
  - Writings of Yehuda Amichai (In Series II) (Box 97, Folder 2217-2219)
  - Writings of Others (In Series III) (Box 97, Folder 2220-2221)
  - Clippings (In Series VI) (Box 97, Folder 2222-2224)
  - Audio cassettes (In Series VII) (Box 98, Folder 2225-2232)
  - Audio cassettes (In Series VII) (Box 98, Folder 2233-2238)
  - Video cassettes (In Series VII) (Box 99, Folder 2239-2246)
  - Video cassettes (In Series VII) (Box 100, Folder 2247-2253)
  - Analog master copy of "Elema valma" (In Series VII), 4 (Box 101, Folder 2254)
  - Film reel of "Nights to Come - 57" (In Series VII) (Box 102 (Cold storage), Folder 2255)
  - Sound reels of "Elem valma" (4 reels) (In Series VII) (Box 103, Folder 2256)
  - Film reels of "Elem valma" (1 of 5) (In Series VII) (Box 104 (Cold storage), Folder 2257)
  - Film reels of "Elem valma" (2 of 5) (In Series VII) (Box 105 (Cold storage), Folder 2258)
  - Film reels of "Elem valma" (3 of 5) (In Series VII) (Box 106 (Cold storage), Folder 2259)
  - Film reels of "Elem valma" (4 of 5) (In Series VII) (Box 107 (Cold storage), Folder 2260)
  - Film reels of "Elem valma" (5 of 5) (In Series VII) (Box 108 (Cold storage), Folder 2261)